Guide to the Meriden Gravure Company Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Meriden Gravure Company records
1895-1990
1900-1977
GEN MSS 606
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
400
(361 boxes) + 1 broadside folder and 1 art object
The Records consist of correspondence, office files, estimates, orders, cost recapitulation forms, proofs, and other material documenting the work of the Meriden Gravure Company, a printing company that rose to prominence in the early twentieth century through specialization in high-fidelity image reproduction.
Meriden Gravure Company
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Meriden-Stinehour Press, 1981-1989, and Stinehour Press, 2006; five additional boxes transferred from Arts of the Book Collection, 2005-2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Meriden Gravure Company
The Meriden Gravure Company was founded in Meriden, Connecticut, in 1888 by Charles Parker and James F. Allen, and grew out of an earlier printing endeavor by Parker.
Driven by the needs of the local silver industry, the company early developed an expertise in high quality image reproduction. It perfected the use of the full-tone collotype printing method, and soon attracted business from other clients who required highly detailed image reproduction, including scientific journals, museums, libraries, and publishers of illustrated books. By the mid-twentieth century, the company was also using offset printing presses, for which it pioneered the use of the fine screened 300-line halftone process for art reproduction and scholarly facsimiles. Both reproduction methods were in use through 1967, when the collotype presses were retired. The company first offered color printing in the 1940s. Through careful quality control, including an insistence on photographing directly from the item to be reproduced and using high quality paper, Meriden Gravure achieved a reputation of consistent excellence in printed illustration.
In addition to an extensive list of academic and museum clients, Meriden Gravure enjoyed steady business from the commercial sphere. The General Electric Company was one of its biggest accounts, as was the United States government (the company earned classified status during World War II).
A driving force behind Meriden Gravure's success from the late 1920s on was E. Harold Hugo (1910-1985), who devoted his entire career to the company. After assisting at age fourteen with experiments to improve the collotype process, he remained dedicated to constant improvements in the quality of reproduction. His passion for fine presswork was additionally enhanced by the influence of printer Gregg Anderson, who worked at the company from 1932 to 1935. Hugo was, by all accounts, an inspired company director and its most energetic salesman. While he never finished college, his expertise and advocacy of fine printing earned him numerous honorary degrees, including an M.A. from Yale in 1963.
The Meriden Gravure Company had a natural counterpart in the Stinehour Press of Lunenberg, Vermont, which was devoted to high quality letterpress printing. The two companies were closely related and often collaborated; Hugo had been on Stinehour's Board of Directors since it was founded in the 1950s. Anticipating Hugo's retirement, the companies merged in 1977. Meriden-Stinehour Press maintained operations in both locations through 1989, when it closed the Meriden operation and moved the presses to Vermont.
Administrative Timeline:
1888 Meriden Gravure Company founded, Meriden, Connecticut
1890 James F. Allen begins as President
1924 Everett Harold Hugo begins work at MGC while in high school
1928 James F. Allen dies; his son Parker Allen becomes President; Hugo drops out of Northeastern University to help run the company
1942-1945 Parker Allen serves in armed forces; Hugo becomes Manager
1943 Hugo becomes Vice President
1962 Hugo becomes President
1975 John Peckham becomes President; Hugo becomes Vice Chairman
1977 MGC merges with Stinehour Press, becoming Meriden-Stinehour Press. Hugo is Chair of the Board
1989 Meriden facility is closed, all operations move to Lunenberg, Vermont
The following works were consulted in preparing this summary:
Peckham, John F. Adventures in printing: a talk on the career of Harold Hugo given at the Club of Odd Volumes. Lunenburg, VT: Stinehour Press, [1995?].
Walker, Gay, Harold Hugo & the Meriden Gravure Company. Wilsonville, Or.: G. Walker, 1995.
Scope and Contents
The Records consist of correspondence, office files, estimates, orders, cost recapitulation forms, proofs, and other material documenting the operation of the Meriden Gravure Company, a commercial printing company that rose to prominence in the early twentieth century through specialization in high-fidelity image reproduction. The records span the dates 1895 to 1990, with the bulk of the material falling between 1900 and 1977.
The records document the work of the company, including its history, internal culture, relationships with clients, and the business of printing. Correspondence between the printing plant in Meriden and the company's New York office documents the internal workings of the company. Correspondence with clients documents specific printing projects, as well as the company's attention to customer's needs. Correspondence can be found throughout the first three series, Office Files, Correspondence, 1900-1959 (arranged largely alphabetically) and Correspondence, 1960-1981 (arranged chronologically), and in Series V. Estimates. Specific print jobs can also be tracked using an order index located in Series V. Orders; the company used an order numbering system that appears to correspond between Series V. Orders, Series VI. Estimates, and Series VII. Recapitulation Forms.
The collection contains numerous examples of the company's work, mostly in proof form, and to some extent documents the technical processes that made it such a success. Of particular interest is a volume of typescript and hand-drawn instructions titled "Collotype Printing" by Arthur Sias, found in Series VII. Financial and Business Records. A run of "Office Records," also in Series VII. is a detailed record of the daily operation of the printing presses from 1895 to 1922.
Examples of the company's detailed reproductions exist chiefly in the Printed Material series, which contains finished samples as well as proofs. Earlier examples such as silver catalogs and postcards exhibit the detail achieved through the collotype process, while later work, such as proofs for Leonard Baskin's illustrations for the Divine Comedy, showcase the company's offset work. Proofs can also be found on the verso of interoffice correspondence.
The records also document the career of E. Harold Hugo, whose personal office files, within the Office Files series, include papers relating to his sales trips for the company, but also files related to his involvement with Old Sturbridge Village and other outside concerns. Hugo's files also include examples of printed matter collected from a number of other presses.
Arrangement
The records are organized into nine series: I. Office Files. II. Correspondence, 1900-1959. III. Correspondence, 1960-1981. IV. Orders. V. Estimates. VI. Recapitulation Forms. VII. Financial and Business Records. VIII. Printed Materials. IX. Meriden-Stinehour, Inc. Records.
Collotype; Offset printing; Photomechanical processes; Printers -- Connecticut -- Meriden; Printing industry -- Connecticut -- Meriden; Printing industry -- United States; Printing -- Connecticut -- Meriden; Collotypes; Offset photomechanical prints; Allen, James F.; Allen, Parker B.; Anderson, Gregg, 1908-1944; Hugo, Harold, 1910-1985; Peckham, John Ford, 1918-; Meriden Gravure Company -- Archives; Meriden-Stinehour Press
- Office Files, circa 1933-1984; Series I; 8; (8 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. Office Files is arranged in alphabetical order by folder title.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Office Files documents the operations of the company between about 1933 and 1984. The files include both internal company correspondence and client correspondence, and reflect the activities of various company personnel as well as the Committee to Honor Harold Hugo (circa 1975 to 1980).
  - Academic Contracts - Atkinson, B. P. correspondence and orders, 1936-1939, circa 1933-1984 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, B. P., correspondence and orders, 1940-1945 (Box 2)
  - Atkinson, B. P., correspondence and orders, 1945 - Barnett, James, 1964, circa 1933-1984 (Box 3)
  - Borger, S. A., 1938 - Hugo, E. H. correspondence, circa 1933-1984 (Box 4)
  - Hugo, E. H. correspondence, circa 1933-1984 (Box 5)
  - Hugo, E. H. correspondence - Hugo, E. H. Old Sturbridge Village, circa 1933-1984 (Box 6)
  - Hugo, E. H. Old Sturbridge Village - Hugo, E. H. miscellaneous, circa 1933-1984 (Box 7)
  - Hugo, E. H. miscellaneous - Vacation Notices, circa 1933-1984 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1900-1959, Series II; 115.75; (91 boxes)
  Series II. Correspondence, 1900-1959 contains general correspondence of the Meriden Gravure Company, including inter-office correspondence and client correspondence. Within General Correspondence, New York Correspondence is comprised of memoranda exchanged between Meriden Gravure Company offices in Meriden, Connecticut and New York City. Correspondence continues in Series III., reflecting a change in the company's filing system in 1960.
  Series II. is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Named Correspondent Files.
  - General Correspondence, 1900-1957
    General Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
    - Bound Correspondence, 1900-1904 (Box 9)
    - New York Correspondence, 1932-1934 (Box 10)
    - General Correspondence, 1933-1947 (Box 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1949-1957 (Box 12)
  - Named Correspondent Files, circa 1933-1959
    Named Correspondent Files are arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent or client.
    - A. B. See Elevator Company - Allis Chalmers Manufacturing, circa 1933-1959 (Box 13)
    - Aluminum Company of America - American Midland Naturalist, circa 1933-1959 (Box 14)
    - American Museum of Natural History - American Printer, circa 1933-1959 (Box 15)
    - American School of Classical Studies - Ansco, circa 1933-1959 (Box 16)
    - Anthoensen Press - Appleton-Century-Crofts, circa 1933-1959 (Box 17)
    - Archaeology Institute of America - Artistic Picture Pub. Co., circa 1933-1959 (Box 18)
    - Artistic Picture Publishing - Baker Raulang Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 19)
    - Baldwin, Shaman - Bernard Picture Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 20)
    - Bernice P. Bishop Museum - Boston National Historic Sites Commission, circa 1933-1959 (Box 21)
    - Boston Public Library - Bulkley-Danton, circa 1933-1959 (Box 22)
    - The Bullard Co. - Carnegie Institute of Technology, circa 1933-1959 (Box 23)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1932-1954 (Box 24)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1955 - Charles Scribner's Sons, circa 1933-1959 (Box 25)
    - Charles T. Branford Company, Publishers - Columbia Broadcasting System, circa 1933-1959 (Box 26)
    - Columbia University, 1932-1942 (Box 27)
    - Columbia University, 1943 - Columbiad Club, 1938, circa 1933-1959 (Box 28)
    - Columbiad Club, 1939 - Cret, Paul Phillippe, circa 1933-1959 (Box 29)
    - Crimson Printing Company - Miscellaneous "C", circa 1933-1959 (Box 30)
    - D'Amour Foundations, Inc. - Derrydale Press, 1934, circa 1933-1959 (Box 31)
    - Derrydale Press, 1935 - Dietz Press, circa 1933-1959 (Box 32)
    - The Dobeckman Company - E. L. Hildreth Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 33)
    - E. P. Dutton & Co. - Miscellaneous "E", circa 1933-1959 (Box 34)
    - F. A. Bassette Company, Printers - Franklin Institute, circa 1933-1959 (Box 35)
    - Franklin Publications, Inc. - Gemsco, Inc., circa 1933-1959 (Box 36)
    - General Electric, 1934-1944 (Box 37)
    - General Electric, 1946-1947 (Box 38)
    - General Electric, 1947-1948 (Box 39)
    - General Electric, 1949-1952 (Box 40)
    - General Electric, 1952-1955 (Box 41)
    - General Electric, 1955 - Genealogical Society of America, 1935, circa 1933-1959 (Box 42)
    - Genealogical Society of America, 1935-1954 (Box 43)
    - Genealogical Society of America, 1955 - The Gorham Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 44)
    - The Gorham Company - Miscellaneous "G", circa 1933-1959 (Box 45)
    - H. B. Fred Huls - Harper & Bros., circa 1933-1959 (Box 46)
    - Harris-Seybold-Potter Co. - Harvard University, 1940, circa 1933-1959 (Box 47)
    - Harvard University, 1941-1947 (Box 48)
    - Harvard University, 1948-1954 (Box 49)
    - Harvard University, 1955-1959 (Box 50)
    - Harvey-Whipple Inc. - Hugh H. Graham & Associates, circa 1933-1959 (Box 51)
    - Hull Printing Company - Miscellaneous "H", circa 1933-1959 (Box 52)
    - I. B. Fischer Co. - J. F. Tapley Co., circa 1933-1959 (Box 53)
    - J. G. Brill Company - Miscellaneous "J", circa 1933-1959 (Box 54)
    - K. R. Sutherland Company - Miscellaneous "K", circa 1933-1959 (Box 55)
    - L. C. Biglow Company - Linton Brothers and Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 56)
    - Linweave - Liturgical Arts Society, circa 1933-1959 (Box 57)
    - Livingston Publishing Company - Machine Composition Co., circa 1933-1959 (Box 58)
    - Mack, Kenneth S. - Manufacturers Assn. of Meriden, circa 1933-1959 (Box 59)
    - Maqua Company - Medallic Art Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 60)
    - Medieval Academy - Merrit Mounting and Finishing, Inc., circa 1933-1959 (Box 61)
    - Merrymount Press - Missouri Historical Society, circa 1933-1959 (Box 62)
    - Mitchell, Giles C. - Museum of New Mexico, circa 1933-1959 (Box 63)
    - Museum of the City of New York - Nelson-Whitehead Paper Corp., circa 1933-1959 (Box 64)
    - New Britain Machine Co. - New York Zoological Society, 1943, circa 1933-1959 (Box 65)
    - New York Zoological Society, 1950 - Oneida Community, Ltd., circa 1933-1959 (Box 66)
    - Onondaga Printing Company - Pantheon Books, 1949, circa 1933-1959 (Box 67)
    - Pantheon Books, 1950 - Peck Studios, circa 1933-1959 (Box 68)
    - The Pierpont Morgan Library - Portsmouth Priory, circa 1933-1959 (Box 69)
    - Pratt and Whitney, 1935-1956 (Box 70)
    - Pratt and Whitney, 1957 - Princeton University, 1940, circa 1933-1959 (Box 71)
    - Princeton University, 1941-1946 (Box 72)
    - Princeton University, 1947-1952 (Box 73)
    - Princeton University, 1953-1956 (Box 74)
    - Princeton University, 1957 - Pulitzer, Joseph J., circa 1933-1959 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous "P" - Reed and Barton, circa 1933-1959 (Box 76)
    - Reed and Stevenson - Royal Parkinson Associates, circa 1933-1959 (Box 77)
    - Rudolph Lesch Fine Arts - Saint Luke's Hospital, circa 1933-1959 (Box 78)
    - Saint Mary's College - Smithsonian Institution, 1953, circa 1933-1959 (Box 79)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 1954 - Southern New England Typographic Service, circa 1933-1959 (Box 80)
    - Southington Printing Company - Stead-Miller Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 81)
    - Steddiford-Pitt Company - Stinehour, Roderick, 1958, circa 1933-1959 (Box 82)
    - Stinehour, Roderick, 1958 - Miscellaneous "S-Se", circa 1933-1959 (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous "Sh" - The Travellers Insurance Co., 1959, circa 1933-1959 (Box 84)
    - Travers Sales Company - U. S. Government Printing Office, 1951, circa 1933-1959 (Box 85)
    - U. S. Government Printing Office, 1952 - University of California, 1949, circa 1933-1959 (Box 86)
    - University of California, 1950 - University of Chicago, 1942, circa 1933-1959 (Box 87)
    - University of Chicago, 1943 - University of Michigan, 1941, circa 1933-1959 (Box 88)
    - University of Michigan, 1943 - University of Oklahoma, 1944, circa 1933-1959 (Box 89)
    - University of Oklahoma, 1945 - University of Southern California, circa 1933-1959 (Box 90)
    - University of Texas - Vassar College, circa 1933-1959 (Box 91)
    - Venspa Company - W. W. Norton and Company, circa 1933-1959 (Box 92)
    - Wace, Mrs. Alan - Westinghouse Electric, circa 1933-1959 (Box 93)
    - Westling Displays - Wildman, F. Collis, circa 1933-1959 (Box 94)
    - William Adams, Inc., Silversmiths - Wycomb-Meyer, Inc., circa 1933-1959 (Box 95)
    - Miscellaneous "W" - Yale University, 1939, circa 1933-1959 (Box 96)
    - Yale University, 1941-1951 (Box 97)
    - Yale University, 1952-1959 (Box 98)
    - Yale University, American Journal of Science - Miscellaneous "Z", circa 1933-1959 (Box 99)
- Correspondence, 1960-1981, Series III; 95; (76 boxes)
  Series III. is organized into three subseries: Scientific Correspondence, New York Correspondence and Other Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged chronologically. Within Other Correspondence, the files for each year are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  Series III. Correspondence, 1960-1981 contains internal and external business correspondence documenting the printing services and operations of the Meriden Gravure Company during the latter part of the twentieth century. The Scientific Correspondence subseries consists of correspondence with scientific clients of Meriden Gravure Company. The New York Correspondence subseries contains memoranda exchanged between Meriden Gravure's offices in Meriden, Connecticut and New York City. Other Correspondence consists of general client correspondence. This second correspondence series reflects a change in the company's filing system in 1960.
  - Scientific Correspondence, 1960-1962
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1960 (Box 100)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1960 (Box 101)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1961 (Box 102)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1961 (Box 103)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1962 (Box 104)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1962 (Box 105)
    - Scientific Correspondence, 1962 (Box 106)
  - New York Correspondence, 1960-1981
    - New York Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 107)
    - New York Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 108)
    - New York Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 109)
    - New York Correspondence, 1964-1981 (Box 110)
  - Other Correspondence, 1960-1977
    - 1960 (Box 111)
    - 1960-1961 "General Electric" (Box 112)
    - 1961 "H" - 1962 "C-D", 1961-1962 (Box 113)
    - 1962 "E-F" - "W-X-Y-Z" (Box 114)
    - 1963 "A" - "G. S. A." (Box 115)
    - 1963 "H" - "N" (Box 116)
    - 1963 "NY Library" - "Texas Press" (Box 117)
    - 1963 "U. S. Govt." - 1964 "C", 1963-1964 (Box 118)
    - 1964 "California" - "I-J-K General" (Box 119)
    - 1964 "L" - "Post Office Receipts" (Box 120)
    - 1964 "Princeton" - "X-Y-Z General" (Box 121)
    - 1964 "Yale University" - 1965 "B", 1964-1965 (Box 122)
    - 1965 "C" - "Harvard University" (Box 123)
    - 1965 "Harvard University" - "O" (Box 124)
    - 1965 "P" - "S" (Box 125)
    - 1965 "T" - 1966 "B, Bollinger, Geo. Braziller Inc.", 1965-1966 (Box 126)
    - 1966 "Boston Athaneum" - "Hugo, E. Harold" (Box 127)
    - 1966 "Library - Harvard University" - "N" (Box 128)
    - 1966 "O General" - "Smithsonian 'Bronzes'" (Box 129)
    - 1966 "So. N. E. Telephone Company, Society of Economics Paleontologists" - 1967 Allen, P. B., 1966-1967 (Box 130)
    - 1967 "Amer. Mus. of Nat Hist. & Micropal" - "F - G" (Box 131)
    - 1967 "G" - "N. York M" (Box 132)
    - 1967 "Mfg.'s Assoc." - "P. I. C." (Box 133)
    - 1967 "R" - "U. S. Govt." (Box 134)
    - 1967 "U-V" - 1968 "A (N. York)", 1967-1968 (Box 135)
    - 1968 "B" - "G" (Box 136)
    - 1968 "Harvard U. - Misc., Press, Peabody Mus., Library" - "Met. Mus." (Box 137)
    - 1968 "Mass. Historical Soc." - "Return Receipts" (Box 138)
    - 1968 "S" - "X-Y-Z" (Box 139)
    - 1969 "A" - "Dartmouth - Dumbarton Oaks" (Box 140)
    - 1969 "D-E-F New York" - "Mfg.'s Assoc" (Box 141)
    - 1969 "Univ. of Mass. & Mass. Review" - "Printing Industry of Conn." (Box 142)
    - 1969 "Q-R" - "Wisconsin" (Box 143)
    - 1969 "Yale U. - Misc." - 1970 "Columbia Univ.", 1969-1970 (Box 144)
    - 1970 "D" - "J-K-L-M New York" (Box 145)
    - 1970 "M" - "P-Q" (Box 146)
    - 1970 "R" - "Wesleyan Univ. - Wisconsin Univ." (Box 147)
    - 1970 "Yale Univ. - Anthropology, Art Hist., Medical School, Misc." - 1971 "Columbia Univ., Cornell, Univ. of Conn.", 1970-1971 (Box 148)
    - 1971 "D" - "H. Hugo Trip File" (Box 149)
    - 1971 "I-J" - "Peabody, Andover & Salem" (Box 150)
    - 1971 "J. F. Peckham Personal" - "N. Y. U-V-W" (Box 151)
    - 1971 "W" - 1972 "Columbia", 1971-1972 (Box 152)
    - 1972 "C-D-E New York" - "M" (Box 153)
    - 1972 "Mass. Hist. Soc." - "N. York R" (Box 154)
    - 1972 "Receipts" - "X-Y-Z" (Box 155)
    - 1973 "A" - "Dumbarton Oaks" (Box 156)
    - 1973 "E" - "H. Hugo Trips" (Box 157)
    - 1973 "I" - "O. S. V. Inquiries" (Box 158)
    - 1973 "P-Q" - "Stinehour Press" (Box 159)
    - 1973 "T" - 1974 "Art Institute of Chicago", 1973-1974 (Box 160)
    - 1974 "B" - "H. Hugo Trip" (Box 161)
    - 1974 "H. Hugo - Grollier Club" - "New York Office - General" (Box 162)
    - 1974 "Old Sturbridge" - "U-V" (Box 163)
    - 1974 "W" - 1975 "B", 1974-1975 (Box 164)
    - 1975 "Amon Carter Museum" - "H. Hugo - Stinehour" (Box 165)
    - 1975 "H" - "O" (Box 166)
    - 1975 "P" - "T" (Box 167)
    - 1975 "W" - 1976 "Univ. of Chicago, Columbia Univ., Univ. of Conn.", 1975-1976 (Box 168)
    - 1976 "D" - "I" (Box 169)
    - 1976 "J" - "Princeton Univ. Press ( R. Passantino) Orders" (Box 170)
    - 1976 "R" - "X-Y-Z" (Box 171)
    - 1977 "A"- "E" (Box 172)
    - 1977 "Europe" - "International Exhibitions" (Box 173)
    - 1977 "J" - "P" (Box 174)
    - 1977 "Q" - "Z" (Box 175)
- Orders, circa 1940-1985; Series IV; 22.13; (23 boxes)
  Series IV. Orders contains order forms and order index cards circa 1940 to 1985. Orders, estimators' worksheets (in Series V.), and recaps (in Series VI.) are stamped in the upper right corner with an order number, which appears to correspond between records. The index cards located in this series correlate client names, job order numbers and dates and may be used to reference specific print jobs. Though dates are not present on all order forms, bundles of sheets were dated on the outer packaging.
  Series IV. is organized into two subseries: Order Index and Order Forms. Order Index is arranged alphabetically by customer name. Order Forms are arranged chronologically and by order number.
  - Order Index, circa 1940-1985
    - Current Order Index A-Q, circa 1940-1985 (Box 176)
    - Order Index Transfers A-J (mostly from 1960 on), circa 1940-1985 (Box 177)
    - Order Index Transfers K-Z (mostly from 1960 on), circa 1940-1985 (Box 178)
  - Order Forms, 1941-1975
    - A-E, 1941-1945 (Box 179)
    - F-H599, 1946-1948 (Box 180)
    - H600-K, 1948-1950 (Box 181)
    - L-M, 1951-1952 (Box 182)
    - N-P, 1953-1954 (Box 183)
    - R-S725, 1955-1956 (Box 184)
    - S726-T, 1956-1957 (Box 185)
    - V-W372, 1958-1959 (Box 186)
    - W373-X725, 1959-1960 (Box 187)
    - X726-A1087, 1960-1961 (Box 188)
    - A1088-B, 1961-1962 (Box 189)
    - C-D291, 1963-1964 (Box 190)
    - D292-E540, 1964-1965 (Box 191)
    - E541-F566, 1965-1966 (Box 192)
    - F570-G798, 1966-1967 (Box 193)
    - G799-J304, 1967-1969 (Box 194)
    - J305-K, 1969-1970 (Box 195)
    - L-M, 1971-1972 (Box 196)
    - P-R431, 1973-1974 (Box 197)
    - R532-S, 1974-1975 (Box 198)
- Estimates, circa 1930-1977; Series V; 39.51; (43 boxes)
  Series V. is organized into three subseries: Estimators' Worksheets: Alphabetical; Estimators' Worksheets: Chronological;and Other Estimates. Within Other Estimates, estimate cards are organized into three alphabetically arranged groups, roughly reflecting the 1930s, 1940s and 1950s, though some overlapping does occur.